Guide to the Andean Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1846-1891; Accession 2013-M-026
  - Peru
    - Title: "East View of Quito and Mount Pichincha, Seen From La Loma De Poingasi." Illustrator: Unknown. Publisher: Unknown., Circa 1850-1895 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Bombardement de Valparaiso par la flotte espagnole, dans la matinée du 31 mars 1886--D'après un croquis de M. Ernest Charton." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: L'Illustration, Journal Universel, pages 312-313., Circa 1850-1895 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Northernmost Chincha (Guano) Island." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 128., 1850 August 17 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Principal Square of Arequipa, in Peru." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 220, 1855 March 10 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Port of Islay, In Peru." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 220., 1855 March 3 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Arica, in Peru, Attacked by the Squadron of General Viranco." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 63., 1857 January 24 (Box 1)
    - Title: " L'escadre espagnole, commandée par l'a(d)miral Pinzon, prend possession des îles Chincha (Pérou)." Illustrator: C. Mavrand. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 370., 1862 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Le grand-maréchal Don Miguel San Roman, président de la République Péruvienne," "Funérailles du grand-maréchal San Roman, célébrées dans la cathédrale de Lima, le 6 avril 1863. (D'apres les photographies de MM. Maunoury (Lima), communiquées par M. Nadar)." Illustrators: L. Chafon, F. Thoriony. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 341. (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Chincha (Guano) Islands: Guano Pile on North Island." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 197., 1863 February 21 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Chincha (Guano) Islands: The Principle Mole," "The Chincha (Guano) Islands: Middle Island, as seen from North Island." Illustrators: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 200., 1863 February 21 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Chincha (Guano) Islands, Peru." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 201., 1863 February 21 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Spanish Iron-Clad Frigate Numancia in the Harbour of Callao." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 313., 1865 September 30 (Box 1)
    - Title: "View of Arica, Peru." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 348, 1865 October 7 (Box 1)
    - Title: The Railway Station, Arica, Peru." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 348, 1865 October 7 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Forts and Batteries at Callao." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 576., 1866 June 16 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Conflict Between the Peruvian Forts and Batteries at Callao and the Spanish Fleet." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, pages 628-629., 1866 June 30 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Lima." Illustrator: W.P. Publication: Unknown., Circa 1870 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Great Earthquake and Tidal Wave on the Peruvian Coast." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Graphic, page 84., 1877 July 28 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Combat Between the British Men-O-War Shah and Amethyst, and the Peruvian Iron-Clad Turret-Ram Huascar." Illustrator: I.R.W. Publication: Harper's Weekly, page 673., 1877 August 25 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The South American War -- Town and Harbour of Iquique, Peru. Scene of the Late Naval Engagement." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Graphic, page 572., 1879 June 14 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Peruvian Ironclad Independencia, Wrecked During a Fight." Illustrator: I.R.W. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 565., 1879 June 14 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The South American War--Action Between the Peruvian Turret-Ship Huascar and the Chilian Ironclads Almirante Cochrane and Blanco Encalada. Illustrator: W.E.A. Publication: The Graphic, page 593., 1879 October 8 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Rear Admiral Gran, Commander of the Peruvian Ram Huascar, Captured by the Chilian Fleet." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Graphic, page 376., 1879 October 18 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Peruvian Monitor Huascar After the Action in Which She Was Captured." Illustrator: I.R.W. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 547., 1879 December 13 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Huascar After The Battle." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Graphic., 1879 December 13 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The War in South America--Sketches in Bolivia and Peru." Illustrator: C.E.J. Publication: The Graphic, page 632., 1879 December 27 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The War Between Chili and Peru." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Pictorial World, page 325., 1880 January 17 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Perou--Une vue de la ville de Lima, récemment prise par l'armée Chilienne--Pont sur le Rimac." Illustrator: Martin. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 68., 1881 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The War in South America--Recruiting for the Peruvian Army in the Cordillera." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Graphic, page 100., 1881 January 29 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The War in South America: Lima, the Capital of Peru, Captured by the Chilian Army." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 133., 1881 February 5 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The War in South America--Lima, Capital of Peru, Captured by the Chilians, January 17th, 1881." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Graphic, page 189., 1881 February 19 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Destruction of the Peruvian Fleet by the Peruvians Before Evacuating Callao." Illustrator: I.R.W. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 228, 1881 March 5 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Recent War in South America--Sketches of the Campaign in Peru." Illustrators: Unknown. Publication: The Graphic, pages 368-369., 1881 April 16 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Effects of War: The Ruins of Chorrillos from Photographs Taken on the Spot After the Conclusion of the Campaign Between Chili and Peru." Illustrators: Unknown. Publication: The Graphic, pages 472-473., 1881 May 14 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Oroya Railway, Peru." Illustrator: P.S. Kellog. Publication: Leisure Hour., 1888 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Plan De Lima (Perou)." Illustrator: Unknown. Publisher: Unknown. Atlas Universel, 1895 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1974-1996; Accession 2015-M-051
  This accession consists of late twentieth-century imprints on various trade unions in Venezuela. The bulk of the materials comes from the period between 1980 and 1995. Trade unions represented in this collection include Confederación de Trabajadores de Venezueula (CTV), Federación de Trabajadores de Venezuela, and Comité por la Defensa del Salario (CDS). Materials include contracts, position papers (including working papers), press releases, copies of newspaper articles and other official union documents.
  - General I, 1974-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General II, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, 1783-1821; Accession 2016-M-081
  - Imported Slave Bill of Sale, 1803 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Imported Slave Bill of Sale, 1810 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Poem: Al Arzobispo Prelado Ilustre, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Broadside: Agustín de Jáuregui y Aldecoa, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, 1992-1995; Accession 2017-M-009
  This accession consists of printed copies of email correspondence compiled by Yale Professor Enrique Mayer compiled during the early days of email listservs in the 1990s. The messages were posted on listservs and discussion boards that focused on the political situation of Peru during this time period by Peruvians living in the United States.
  - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)